explara.com 2018-12-17

# Privacy Policy |Explara.com

##### Last updated: April 23, 2018

## Privacy Policy

We work hard to earn and keep your trust, therefore your privacy is our top most focus.

#### Information Collection

We collect information during registration, use of the services site, communicating with site members, admin, using content, content upload to our site. We also receive information about your IP address, cookies and pages you visited. Such information are collected to provide best service, research, and overall product experience. 

#### Information Sharing

We will always obtain your prior specific consent before we share or disclose your personally identifiable information to any partner, and user. We are also accountable to disclose user information and the contents of the Accounts to the local law enforcement authorities under specifically defined circumstances. In case Explara service gets merged or acquired, we will be informing on the website about such developments. 

In case your profile is public, or your details are in public domain in our site, you will receive unsolicited messages from users in Explara.com and from external sources.

When you have opted for receiving related information, we will use your information to show you relevant advertisements, contents, events from us and our partners. Access to your name, email address and private details is restricted to our employees who need to know such information in connection with our services and are bound by confidentiality obligations. 

#### Explara GDPR complaint 

The General Data Protection Regulation [GDPR]  
Effective May 25th, 2018, the GDPR[General Data Protection Regulation] will be in effect for EU resident. In this regard, Explara has updated its privacy policy, cookies policies so that event organisers and consumers are comfortable that our updated policy meets the new requirement. 

##### Explara - the Data controller 

When an event organiser creates account on Explara in order to use the platform, Explara becomes the data controller of the data that is provided by the event organiser as part of the account opening process.   
"If a consumer provides personal details during the course of creating an account then in that case, Explara becomes the data controller of the data provided by the consumer to Explara. Explara would also be the controller of those data or details provided by the consumer or the event organiser for the usage of other services offered by Explara" 

##### Explara - The data processor

"Explara provides various services to the consumer on behalf of the organiser such as issuing E-ticket for an event, sending emails to the consumer on behalf of the organiser, processing online and offline payments, event marketing reports that analyze the effectiveness of various sales channel".   
"With this, it is evident that Explara during the course of its service offering whether on behalf of the event organiser or directly to the consumer, Explara may be both Controller as well as Processor." 

##### Data Removal

"Explara as a data controller of the event organiser's data allows the organiser to remove the data of the Consumer from the dashboard of the event. This can be accomplished by removing the event from the dashboard. In such cases, the event organiser will not be able to see the data. Organisers can also delete their non financial data of an event. In such cases, the personal data of the organiser will be removed and at the same time, the personal data of the consumer will be anonymized. But in any case, the financial data of the attendee remains with the system for quite sometime to fight chargeback or any other financial dispute with the regulatory agencies or bank."   
In case any of the attendee or the consumer wants Explara to remove the personal data from the system, a delete request mail can be sent to [privacy@signure.com](mailto:privacy@signure.com) for further action. 

##### Email Communication 

"Email is an important part of event ticketing and as part of solution offering, Explara provides options for event organisers to send emails to event attendees. It is up to the event organiser to use this feature for event marketing purpose. In event of this, the event organiser has to comply with the opt-in consent. Since Explara is just the solution provider, it doesn't send any mail for or on-behalf of the organiser."

#### Cookies

We use 'session' cookies for a browser session, we also store cookies in your computer to access your login information, and preferences. We use cookies to enhance your experience of our services. 

#### IP Address

When you visit Explara.com, we receive the Internet protocol (IP) address of your computer, operating system information, browser information and name of your ISP. This information is used to improve our service offerings, we are also legally accountable to pass the same information to legal authorities when requested. We also advanced web analytics, which provides information such as the URL of the site from which you came and the site to which you are going. 

#### Links from Our Website

We have many pages containing external links. You are advised to verify the privacy practices of such externally linked websites. We are not responsible for the manner of use or misuse of information made available by you at such other websites. We encourage you not to provide Personal Information, without assuring yourselves of the privacy policy of external linked websites. 

#### How Secure is Your Information

We adopt appropriate data collection, storage and processing practices and security measures, as well as physical security measures to protect against unauthorized access, alteration, disclosure or destruction of your Personal Information, username, password, transaction information and data stored in your Account.

Our employees also sign confidentiality agreements to use your data for product enhancement, bug fixes and for services only.

#### Notification of Changes

When there are significant changes to the privacy policy, the same will be posted on our websites in order to keep you informed of any changes in nature of information collected, manner of collection, use and sharing of information.

#### Conflicts Between Privacy Policy & Terms

At any time, when there is a conflict between the terms of service and the privacy policy, the Terms shall control. 

We don't provide service to children under age 16, therefore we don't collect information and privacy policy makes no provision for children's use of the site. 

If you have any questions, suggestions and comments regarding this privacy policy, please contact us at [info@explara.com](mailto:info@explara.com). 

## Cookie Policy

#### Cookies

A cookie is a small text file which is automatically saved on your computer when you visit our website and is used to help track activity across a website.

#### 1st party cookies

These cookies are strictly necessary to provide you essential services that we serves with .explara.com and related partner’s whitelabel domains. Because these cookies are necessary, you can not refuse them. You may block or delete them by changing your browser settings.

#### Google Analytics & Third Party

We use Google Analytics & Third party tools to help provide anonymous web analytics for our website.

#### Website

We use cookies to help increase the user experience of this website.

#### Removing cookies

If you have any concerns about cookies, or want to remove cookies from your computer, please visit [All About Cookies](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/) which explains how to do this.

#### Changes to this cookies policy

Our policies and procedures are under continual review. We may, from time to time, update our cookies policy. Any such changes will be posted on this page.

#### Collection of personal information

If you contact us via a form on our website your personal information will only be used for us to contact you. No personal data you send us will be disclosed to a third party without your permission. If you wish us to remove any personal details we hold about you, please email us at [privacy@signure.com](mailto:privacy@signure.com)
